A Guide to the University of Connecticut 1979.0014
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series VII: Research Materials on Ethnicity and Immigration, undated, 1936-1979
  - Ethnicity in Connecticut
    - "Minority Group Integration by Labor and Management", 1953 (Box 14, Folder 587)
    - "Minority Pupils and Staff in the Public Schools of CT", 1978 (Box 14, Envelope 588)
    - "New Study of College Admissions Practices with Respect to Race, Religion and National Origin", 1953 (Box 14, Folder 589)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1973-1979 (Box 14, Folder 590)
    - "Our Roots" Project, undated (Box 14, Folder 591)
    - "The People of Connecticut", undated (Box 14, Folder 592)
    - "Private Interracial Neighborhoods in CT", 1957 (Box 14, Folder 593)
    - Rank ordering of CT's ethnic groups, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 594)
    - "Report on CT: Family Relocation under Urban Renewal", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 595)
    - Sheeley, Robert George, "An Historical Review of a Social Settlement", 1974 (Box 14, Folder 596)
    - Steahr, Thomas E., Ethnic Atlas of CT, 1970, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 597)
    - Steahr, Thomas E., and Charles N. Fitts, "Births, Deaths and Net Migration by Age for Townships, CT, 1960-1970", 1975 (Box 14, Folder 598)
    - "A Study of Urban School Needs in the Five Largest Cities in CT", 1969 (Box 14, Folder 599)
    - Whetten, Nathan L., and Arnold W. Green, "Ethnic Group Relations in a Rural Area of CT", 1943 (Box 14, Folder 600)
    - Whetten, Nathan L., and Henery W. Riecken, Jr., "The Foreign-born Population of CT, 1940", 1943 (Box 14, Folder 601)
  - Ethnicity
    - Allen, Irving Lewis, "WASP: From Sociological Concept to Epithet", 1974 (Box 14, Folder 602)
    - Denfeld, D., "Racial-Ethnic Identification in Prisons", 1972 (Box 14, Folder 603)
    - "Ethnicity and Race", 1974 (Box 14, Folder 604)
    - Gabriel, Richard A. and Paul L. Savage, "The Ethnicity Attribute", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 605)
    - Giordano, Joseph, Ethnicity and Mental Health, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 606)
    - Giordano, Joseph, "Servicing and Organizing the White Ethnic Community", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 607)
    - Greely, Andrew M., The Rediscovery of Diversity, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 608)
    - Kutner, Nance G., "An Inter-ethic and Place of Residence Examination of the 'Culture of Poverty'", 1975 (Box 14, Folder 609)
    - Levine, Irving and Judith Herman, "Group Conflict, Group Interest, and Group Identity", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 610)
    - Mamone, John R., "Social Bonds Among Ethnic Groups", undated (Box 14, Folder 611)
    - Montalto, Nicholas V., "Modifying the Small Group Experience for Multi-Cultural America", undated (Box 14, Folder 612)
    - Multi-Cultural Calendar, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 613)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 14, Folder 614)
    - Novak, Michael, "Further Thoughts on Ethnicity", undated (Box 14, Folder 615)
    - Review of Jacob A. Riis Photographer and Citizen, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 616)
    - Seifer, Nancy, "The New Ethnocide", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 617)
    - Shimahara, Nobuo K., "Social Justice, Neo-ethnicity and Ethnic Heritage Studies", undated (Box 14, Folder 618)
    - Stepuchin, Peggy, "Multi-Cultural Party and Festival Games", 1979 (Box 14, Folder 619)
    - Vecoli, Rudolph J., "Ethnicity, A Neglected Dimension American History", 1970 (Box 14, Folder 620)
    - Tomasi, Lydio F., "The Ethnic Factor in the Future of Inequality", undated (Box 14, Folder 621)
    - Vecoli, Rudolph J., "European Americans: From Immigrants to Ethnic", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 622)
    - Walden, Daniel, "Pennsylvania: An Ethnic Sampler", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 623)
    - Williams, Melvin G., "Whatever Became of the Melting Pot?", 1973 (Box 14, Folder 624)
  - Ethnicity (Periodicals)
    - American Folklore Newsletter, 1977-1978 (Box 14, Folder 625)
    - Bulletin of the Cross-Cultural Southwest Ethnic Study Center, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 626)
    - EMPAC, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 627)
    - Ethnic America, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 628)
    - Ethnic News, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 629)
    - The Ethnic Voice of Cleveland, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 630)
    - Ethnicity, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 631)
    - Heritage, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 632)
    - Heritage Exchange, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 633)
    - ISR Newsletter, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 634)
    - Mosaic, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 635)
    - A New America, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 636)
    - News from the Committee (American Jewish Committee), 1973 (Box 14, Folder 637)
    - Pennsylvania Ethnic Studies Newsletter, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 638)
    - Spectrum, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 639)
    - Viewpoint, undated (Box 14, Folder 640)
    - World Cultural Heritage, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 641)
  - Reference Materials on Ethnicity
    - Immigration and Naturalism laws, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 642)
    - Ethnic Media, undated (Box 15, Folder 643)
    - The Greater Cleveland Nationalities Directory, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 644)
    - Stetler, Henry G., The Socialist Movement in Reading, PA, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 645)
    - The International Migration Review, 1970-1972 (Box 15, Folder 646)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service, Annual Report, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 647)
    - Children's Multi-Cultural Materials, undated (Box 15, Folder 648)
    - Archive holdings on ethnicity, undated (Box 15, Folder 649)
    - Ethnic bibliographies, undated (Box 15, Folder 650-653)
    - Publishers catalogues and announcements, undated (Box 15, Folder 654-655)
  - Other Ethnic Programs
    - "The Hartford Training the Teacher of Teacher Programs", 1972 (Box 15, Folder 656)
    - Other Ethnic program is Connecticut, undated (Box 15, Folder 657-659)
    - Teacher Training programs in ethnicity (CT), undated (Box 15, Folder 660)
    - Ethnic Heritage Studies, Curriculum Units, Cleveland Public Schools, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 661-665)
    - Other programs in U.S., (Alabama, Alaska, Boston, California, Colorado), undated (Box 16, Folder 666)
    - In U.S., (Illinois, Indiana, Massachusetts, Michigan, Minnesota, Missouri), undated (Box 16, Folder 667)
    - In U.S., (Nevada), undated (Box 16, Folder 668)
    - In U.S. (New Jersey, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Texas, Virginia, Washington D.C., Wisconsin), undated (Box 16, Folder 669)
    - Gambino, Richard, "A Guide to Ethnic Studies Programs in American Colleges, Universities and Schools", 1975 (Box 16, Folder 670)
    - Kotler, Greta and Violetta Kuncaitis, "Bibliography of Ethnic Heritage Studies Program Materials", 1976 (Box 16, Folder 671)
    - Ethnic Heritage Studies Program (HEW), 1974 (Box 16, Folder 672)
    - Teacher Training Programs in Ethnicity, undated (Box 16, Envelope 673)
    - Other programs, (Canada, England), undated (Box 16, Folder 674)
- Series VIII: Research Materials on Local History, undated, 1930-1979
  - Groton
    - Althuis, Rose Marie, "The Village of Groton Bank", 1974 (Box 17, Folder 675)
    - Larrabee, Betsy Barber, "The Story of the Battle of Fort Griswold", 1967 (Box 17, Folder 675A)
  - Hartford
    - First Presbyterian Church, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 676)
    - Garilli, Gloria and George Grisevich, "Hartford in History", undated (Box 17, Folder 677)
    - Johnson, Kaye, "Highlights of Modern Hartford", undated (Box 17, Folder 678)
    - Landmarks, undated (Box 17, Folder 679)
    - "Potential Housing Abandonment in Hartford," HURG, undated (Box 17, Folder 680)
  - Litchfield
    - Litchfield: Portrait of a Beautiful Town, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 681)
  - Middletown
    - The First Baptist Church, undated (Box 17, Folder 682)
  - Norwalk
    - Lockwood House, undated (Box 17, Folder 683)
  - Pomfret
    - Pomfret School, undated (Box 17, Folder 684)
  - Stamford
    - First Presbyterian Church, undated (Box 17, Folder 685)
  - Stonington
    - Crandall, Katherine B., The Fine Old Town of Stonington, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 686)
  - Waterbury
    - Waterbury: A Pictorial History, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 687)
  - Wethersfield
    - First Church of Christ, Buttolph-Williams House, Webb/Deane/Stevens Museums, undated (Box 17, Folder 688)
  - Windsor
    - Windsor Historic Clubs and Organizations, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 689)
  - Connecticut History
    - Bibliographies and resource, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 690)
    - The Catholic Church in Connecticut, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 691)
    - Connecticut Baptists, undated (Box 17, Folder 692)
    - Southwest CT's role in the American Revolution, undated (Box 17, Folder 692A)
    - Connecticut State Register and Manual, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 693)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1976? (Box 14, Folder 694)
    - Pamphlets and periodicals, 1975-1979 (Box 17, Folder 695)
  - United States and General History
    - Cleveland, Ohio; Massachusetts; General, undated (Box 17, Folder 696)
- Series IX: Administrative Records, undated
  - Agendas (Box 18, Envelope 697)
  - Americans Jewish Committee (Box 18, Folder 698)
  - Correspondence (Box 18, Folder 699-704)
  - Employment authorizations (Box 18, Folder 705)
  - Form letters (Box 18, Folder 706)
  - Foundations/institute (Box 18, Folder 707)
  - Grant proposal preparation (Box 18, Folder 708)
  - Grant data (Box 18, Folder 709)
  - Historical societies (Box 18, Folder 710)
  - Minutes (Box 18, Folder 711)
  - Native American data (Box 18, Folder 712)
  - Oral histories (Box 18, Folder 713)
  - Peoples of Connecticut Advisory Council (Box 18, Folder 714)
  - Philadelphia Social History Project (Box 18, Folder 715)
  - Reports (Box 18, Folder 716)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 18, Folder 717)
  - Rutgers Inter-Cultural Relations and Ethnic Studies Institute (Box 18, Folder 718)
  - Social Research, Inc. (Box 18, Folder 719)
  - Southwest Ethnic Study Center (Box 18, Folder 720)
  - Vitaes (Box 18, Folder 721-722)
- Series X: William D'Antonio Files, undated
  - Acts of Congress (Box 18, Folder 723)
  - Bibliographies (Box 18, Folder 724)
  - Course prospective (Box 18, Folder 725)
  - Dissertation proposal: Crispero, James (Box 18, Folder 726)
  - Ethnic data: miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 727)
  - Ethnic Heritage Studies Curriculum Development Project (Box 18, Folder 728)
  - Ethnic Study Center (Box 18, Folder 729)
  - Institute on Pluralism and Group Identity (Box 18, Folder 730)
  - National Project on Ethnic America (Box 18, Folder 731)
  - Oral histories (Box 18, Folder 732)
  - Papers: miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 733)
  - Studies
    - Cultural and Social Reactions to Pain (Box 18, Folder 734)
    - Immigration and America's Ethnic Heritage (Box 18, Folder 735)
    - Pain: Anxiety and Attitudes in Black, White, and Puerto Rican Patients (Box 18, Folder 736)
    - Records of the Work Projects Administration, CT, 1935-1944 (Box 18, Folder 737)
  - TASK (Box 18, Folder 738)
  - Thesis: An Historical Review of a Social Contract (Box 18, Folder 7439)
  - Theses (Box 18, Folder 740-741)
  - Vita (Box 18, Folder 742)
- Series XI: Research Materials on Ethnic Groups, undated, 1974-1976
  - American Italian Historical Association (Box 19, Folder 743)
  - European Americans from Immigrants to Ethics (Box 19, Folder 744)
  - Guide to Ethnic Studies Programs in American Colleges, Universities and Schools (Box 19, Folder 745)
  - Liberty and Justice For All (Box 19, Folder 746)
  - Orchard Lake Center for Polish Studies and Culture (Box 19, Folder 747)
  - Polish-American of South Bend (Box 19, Folder 748)
  - Newsletters
    - ACIM (Box 19, Folder 749)
    - The Afro American (Box 19, Folder 750)
    - Congress of Italian-American Organizations, Inc. (Box 19, Folder 751)
    - Connecticut Association of Local Legislators (Box 19, Folder 752)
    - The COSSMHO Reporter (Box 19, Folder 753)
    - Cross-Cultural Ethnic Study Center (Box 19, Folder 754)
    - EMPAC (Box 19, Folder 755)
    - Enfield (Box 19, Folder 756)
    - Ethnic Heritage Curriculum Materials Project, Colorado (Box 19, Folder 747)
    - Heritage Exchange (Box 19, Folder 758)
    - Institute for Social Research (Box 19, Folder 759)
    - Italian Heritage (Box 19, Folder 760)
    - Items: Social Science Research Center (Box 19, Folder 761)
    - MOSAIC (Box 19, Folder 762)
    - New Haven (Box 19, Folder 763)
    - Pennsylvania - Ethnic Studies (Box 19, Folder 764)
    - Wayne State University (Box 19, Folder 765)
  - Newspapers
    - The American Weekly, 1976 February (Box 19, Folder 766)
    - The Advocate, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 767-774)
    - Irish Echo, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 775-789)
    - Italian-American News, 1974 September (Box 19, Folder 790)
    - Italian-American News, 1975 January (Box 19, Folder 791)
- Series XII: Photographs, undated
  - Italians in America (Box 20, Folder 792-800)